Gerrit Smith Papers
Gerrit Smith Papers
- Correspondence
  - General Correspondence
    - Rogers, M. – Rook, 1842-1874 (Box 31)
    - Roos – Rose, A.C., 1847-1872 (Box 32)
    - Rose, D. – Roy, 1834-1874 (Box 32)
    - Rud – Rut, 1827-1874 (Box 32)
    - Sac – Sand, 1846-1874 (Box 32)
    - Sampson, G.C., 1838-1874; 2 folders (Box 32)
    - Sanf – Say, 1845-1874 (Box 32)
    - Sanger, H.K., 1839-1861 (Box 32)
    - Sawyer, Leicester Ambrose, 1862-1874; 2 folders (Box 32)
    - Sca – Sch, 1839-1870 (Box 32)
    - Schoolcraft, Henry Rowe and Mary Howard, 1854-1874; 24 letters and 1 item of non-correspondence (Box 32)
    - Schurz, Carl, 1858-1859; 3 letters (Box 32)
    - Sco – Scott, 1841-1874 (Box 32)
    - Scov – Scr, 1863-1874 (Box 33)
    - Sea – Sey, 1841-1874 (Box 33)
    - Sedgwick, Charles B., 1852; undated (Box 33)
    - Sedgwick, C.H., 1872-1874 (Box 33)
    - Seward, William Henry, 1842-1853; undated; 22 letters (Box 33)
    - Sha – Shaw, 1854-1873 (Box 33)
    - She – Shel, 1832-1874 (Box 33)
    - Shep – Sherwi, 1847-1874 (Box 33)
    - Sherwa – Shr, 1836-1868 (Box 33)
    - Eib – Simo, 1839-1872 (Box 33)
    - Sims – Sis, 1858-1874 (Box 33)
    - Ski – Sly, 1837-1871 (Box 33)
    - Sma – Smith, A., 1840-1874 (Box 33)
    - Smith, B. – J.S., 1839-1874 (Box 33)
    - Smith, James – Smith, R.M., 1848-1874 (Box 33)
    - Smith, S. – Sny, 1836-1874 (Box 33)
    - Smith, Elizabeth Oakes Prince, 1832-1867; 9 letters, 1 poem (Box 34)
    - Smith, James McCune, 1839-1864 (Box 34)
    - Smith, James Milton, 1873 (Box 34)
    - Sol – Spea, 1833-1874 (Box 34)
    - Spee – Spencer, O., 1828-1873 (Box 34)
    - Spencer, E. – Spencer, W., 1836-1873 (Box 34)
    - Sper – Squ, 1837-1874 (Box 34)
    - Sta – Stat, 1845-1874 (Box 34)
    - Stanton, Elizaþeth Cady, 1850-1873; undated; 41 letters (Box 34)
    - Stanton, Freeman, 1841-1842; 9 letters (Box 34)
    - Stanton, Henry Brewster, 1834-1873; undated; 47 letters, 1 item of non-correspondence (Box 34)
    - Stea – Stebbins, C., 1826-1814 (Box 34)
    - Stebbins, G. – Stee, 1847-1874 (Box 34)
    - Stei – Stew, 1834-1874 (Box 34)
    - Stîc – Stin, 1845-1870 (Box 34)
    - Stoc – Ston, 1834-1874 (Box 34)
    - Stone, Lucy, 1854-1873; 7 letters (Box 35)
    - Stow – Stowe, 1841-1874 (Box 35)
    - Stowe, Harriet Beecher, 1852; 1 letter (Box 35)
    - Str – Stu, 1832-1874 (Box 35)
    - Stuart, Charles, 1835-1863; 5 folders (Box 35)
    - Stuart, Rebecka, 1859-1879; 3 folders (Box 35)
    - Sturge, Joseph, 1839-1858; 11 letters (Box 35)
    - Sud – Swe, 1837-1874 (Box 35)
    - Sullivan, John W., 1855-1873; 2 folders (Box 35)
    - Sumner, Charles, 1845-1875; 35 letters and 3 items non-correspondence (Box 35)
    - Sweet, Samuel N., 1841-1874; 2 folders (Box 35)
    - Swi – Syk, 1831-1872 (Box 35)
    - Tac – Tal, 1836-1874 (Box 35)
    - Taft, S.H., 1856-1874 (Box 36)
    - Talcott, E.B., 1865-1869 (Box 36)
    - Tan – Taylor, G., 1856-1874 (Box 36)
    - Tappan, Arthur, 1856 (Box 36)
    - Tappan, John, 1834-1868 (Box 36)
    - Tappan, Lewis
      - [General], 1832-1870; undated; 7 folders (Box 36)
      - to Seth M. Gates, 1840-1842 (Box 36)
      - Non-correspondence items, 1852-1855 (Box 36)
    - Taylor, H. – Ter, 1836-1873 (Box 36)
    - Tha – The, 1848-1874 (Box 36)
    - Tho – Thomas, 1839-1874 (Box 36)
    - Thomas, John, 1847-1872 (Box 36)
    - Thompson – Thu, 1846-1874 (Box 37)
    - Tif – Titler, E., 1835-1872 (Box 37)
    - Tilton, Theodore, 1863-1870; 8 items (Box 37)
    - Titler, N. – Titu, 1839-1874 (Box 37)
    - Tob – Tor, 1834-1874 (Box 37)
    - Tou – Toz, 1848-1872 (Box 37)
    - Tra – Tred, 1840-1874 (Box 37)
    - Trask, George, 1852-1874 (Box 37)
    - Trev – Try, 1837-1874 (Box 37)
    - Truth, Sojourner, 1863-1871 (Box 37)
    - Tuck – Turner, E., 1837-1872 (Box 37)
    - Turner, J. – Turner, R., 1831-1873 (Box 37)
    - Turner, T. – Tyl, 1835-1873 (Box 37)
    - Uff – Underwood, 1848-1874 (Box 37)
    - Une – Utt, 1842-1874 (Box 37)
    - Vad – Viv, 1826-1872 (Box 37)
    - Van Buren, Martin, 1830-1831; 3 items (Box 37)
    - Van Rensselaer, See also Rensselaer surname.
    - Van Rensselaer, Cortlandt, 1832-1834 (Box 37)
    - Van Rensselaer, Stephen, 1828 (Box 37)
    - Van Santwood, Adrían, 1850-1856 (Box 37)
    - Van Vechten, Jacob, 1836-1874; 2 folders (Box 38)
    - Wad – Wag, 1858-1873 (Box 38)
    - Wai – Walk, 1858-1873 (Box 38)
    - Wall – Walton, E., 1838-1871 (Box 38)
    - Walton, J. – Waln, 1839-1874 (Box 38)
    - Wan – Warn, 1838-1874 (Box 38)
    - Ward, Samuel Ringgold, 1842-1854 (Box 38)
    - Warr – Waterm, 1858-1874 (Box 38)
    - Waters – Watkins, 1830- 1874 (Box 38)
    - Wats – Watson, W., 1828-1868 (Box 38)
    - Watt – Way, 1841-1862 (Box 38)
    - Wayland, Francis, 1853 (Box 38)
    - Wea – Webb, R., 1845-1874 (Box 38)
    - Webb, S. – Welle, 1837-1874 (Box 38)
    - Weed, Thurlow, 1852-1874; 3 items (Box 38)
    - Weld, Angelina Grimke, 1854-1872; 7 items (Box 38)
    - Weld, Theodore Dwight, 1838-1871; 30 items (Box 38)
    - Welli – Wells, L., 1825-1871 (Box 38)
    - Wells, S. – Wer, 1846-1867 (Box 38)
    - Wes – West, 1845-1869 (Box 38)
    - Weth – Wett, 1836-1871 (Box 38)
    - Wha – Whea, 1851-1873 (Box 38)
    - Wheel – Wheelw, 1837-1873 (Box 39)
    - Wheeler, Edward, 1859-1872 (Box 39)
    - Whip – White, S., 1835-1873 (Box 39)
    - Whipple, George, 1849-1874 (Box 39)
    - White, T. – Whitt, 1846-1874 (Box 39)
    - White, Andrew D., 1862-1874; 12 items (Box 39)
    - Whittier, John Greenleaf, 1840-1873; 6 items (Box 39)
    - Whitewall, S.W., 1858-1859 (Box 39)
    - Wic – Wig, 1832-1872 (Box 39)
    - Wilb – Wilk, 1848-1873 (Box 39)
    - Will – Williams, D.W., 1839-1874 (Box 39)
    - Willard, Frances, 1874; 1 item (Box 39)
    - Williams, D. – Williams, R., 1834-1874 (Box 39)
    - Williams, S. – Willy, 1836-1874 (Box 39)
    - Williams, E[lisha], 1819-1854; 2 folders (Box 39)
    - Wilmot, David, 1856; 1 item (Box 39)
    - Wils – Wilson, W., 1847-1874 (Box 39)
    - Wilson, Henry, 1838-1874; 11 items (Box 39)
    - Win – Wint, 1847-1874 (Box 39)
    - Wis – Wiz, 1856-1869 (Box 40)
    - Wob – Wood, W., 1832-1874 (Box 40)
    - Woodb – Wool, 1824-1874 (Box 40)
    - Woodhull, Victoria, 1871; 1 item (Box 40)
    - Wor – Wright, F., 1851-1874 (Box 40)
    - Wright, H. – Wyn, 1841-1873 (Box 40)
    - Wright, Elizur, 1834-1873 (Box 40)
    - Wright, H.C., 1839-1862 (Box 40)
    - Wright, Theodore, 1834-1835; 4 items (Box 40)
    - Yal – Yos, 1825-1873 (Box 40)
    - Young – Young, 1841-1871 (Box 40)
    - Zac – Zuo, 1852-1870 (Box 40)
    - Anonymous (Box 40)
    - Illegible signatures (Box 40)
    - Pseudonyms (Box 40)
    - Transcripts and photocopies (Box 40)
    - Letters addressed to others than Gerrit Smith, his family or relatives (Box 40)
  - Outgoing letters
    - Letter copybook, 1827-1843 (Volume 1)
    - Letter copybook, 1843-1855 (Volume 2)
    - [General], 1815 Jun-1859 Dec; 28 folders (Box 41)
    - [General], 1860 Feb-1874 Nov; 12 folders (Box 42)
  - Business correspondence
    - Undated, 2 folders (Box 43)
    - 1809-1826, 17 folders (Box 43)
    - 1827-1831 Apr, 9 folders (Box 44)
    - 1831 May-1834 Jul, 9 folders (Box 45)
    - 1834 Aug-1837 Feb, 8 folders (Box 46)
    - 1837 Mar-1838 Jul, 9 folders (Box 47)
    - 1838 Aug-1840 Aug, 7 folders (Box 48)
    - 1840 Sep-1842 Aug, 6 folders (Box 49)
    - 1842 Sep-1844 Dec, 7 folders (Box 50)
    - 1845 Jan-1846 Dec, 9 folders (Box 51)
    - 1847 Jan-1848 Dec, 6 folders (Box 52)
    - 1849 Jan-1850 Dec, 7 folders (Box 53)
    - 1851 Jan-1853 Feb, 7 folders (Box 54)
    - 1853 Mar-1855 Dec, 9 folders (Box 55)
    - 1856 Jan-1858 Jun, 9 folders (Box 56)
    - 1858 Jul-1859 Dec, 7 folders (Box 57)
    - 1860 Jan-1862 Jan, 9 folders (Box 58)
    - 1862 Feb-1864 Dec, 11 folders (Box 59)
    - 1865 Jan-1867 Dec, 9 folders (Box 60)
    - 1868 Jan-1870 Dec, 12 folders (Box 61)
    - 1871 Jan-1873 Dec, 11 folders (Box 62)
    - 1874-1889, 4 folders (Box 63)
  - Family correspondence
    - Andrews, Ann (cousin), 1849-1877 (Box 63)
    - Backus, Azel, 1855-1870 (Box 63)
    - Backus, Frederick F. and Rebecca A., 1819-1861 (Box 63)
    - Backus, Frederick W., 1848-1860; 2 folders (Box 63)
    - Backus, Montgomery, Gerrit Fitzhugh and Rebecca, 1866-1869 (Box 63)
    - Backus family, 1808-1874; undated; 2 folders (Box 63)
    - Baird, Cornelia W. (Smith), 1847-1873 (Box 63)
    - Barclay, Cornelia (Cochrane), 1848-1869 (Box 63)
    - Barclay family, miscellaneous, 1847-1873 (Box 63)
    - Bayard, Tryphena, 1826-1870 (Box 63)
    - Biddle, Chapman, 1855-1869 (Box 64)
    - Biddle, Mary L. (Cochrane), 1850-1873 (Box 64)
    - Biddle, Walter L.C., 1873 (Box 64)
    - Brent, Welthea A. (niece), 1858-1874 (Box 64)
    - Cady, Daniel (uncle), 1819-1859 (Box 64)
    - Cady, Daniel W., 1874; 12 folders (Box 64)
    - Cochrane, Cornelia W. (Smith), 1805-1847; undated; 4 folders (Box 64)
    - Cochran, Major James, 1819-1842 (Box 64)
    - Cochrane, James W., 1839-1870 (Box 65)
    - Cochrane, John, 1835-1866; undated; 4 folders (Box 65)
    - Cochrane, Peter, 1834-1841; undated (Box 65)
    - Cochrane, Walter L., 1870-1874 (Box 65)
    - Cochrane family to GS and others, 1823-1873 (Box 65)
    - Fitzhugh, David H., 1833-1873 (Box 65)
    - Fitzhugh, George, 1850-1874 (Box 65)
    - Fitzhugh, Henry
      - 1823-1831, 7 folders (Box 65)
      - 1832-1865, 6 folders (Box 66)
    - Fitzhugh, William to GS and Ann (Fitzhugh) Smith, 1821-1847; 3 folders (Box 66)
    - Fitzhugh family, 1823-1874; undated; 3 folders (Box 66)
    - Henry, Catherine (aunt), 1826-1869 (Box 66)
    - Kemeys, Catherine S. (Cochrane), 1830-1874 (Box 66)
    - Kemeys, William, 1849-1873 (Box 66)
    - Livingston, James, 1842-1850 (Box 66)
    - Livingston family, 1817-1870 (Box 66)
    - Miller, Anne Fitzhugh, 1868 (Box 66)
    - Miller, Charles D., 1845-1869; incoming only (Box 66)
    - Miller, Charles D., Jr., 1867-1874 (Box 67)
    - Miller, Elizabeth Smith (Mrs. Charles D.; "Bessie")
      - to GS and Ann Carrol (Fitzhugh) Smith, 1831-1877; 6 folders (Box 67)
      - to her father Gerrit Smith; incoming only, 1860-1897 (Box 67)
    - Miller, Gerrit Smith, 1867-1874 (Box 67)
    - Miller, William Fitzhugh, 1873-1874 (Box 67)
    - Miller family, 1861-1881 (Box 67)
    - Pitcher, Emily Backus, 1859-1874 (Box 67)
    - Smïth, Ann C. (Fitzhugh)
      - Incoming, 1824-1875 (Box 67)
      - to Betsey Fitzhugh, 1827-1835 (Box 67)
      - to Elizabeth (Smith) Miller and others, 1834-1840; 1843,; undated; 4 folders (Box 67)
      - to Elizabeth (Smith) Miller and others, 1844-1874; 14 folders (Box 68)
      - to GS, 1823-1846; undated; 9 folders (Box 68)
      - to GS, 1849-1874; 8 folders (Box 69)
      - to Peter Smith and others, 1822-1843 (Box 69)
    - Smith, Ann Van Buskirk (Prentiss) to Peter Skenandoah Smith, 1831-1832 (Box 69)
    - Smith, Ann E. (Cumming) to GS and others, 1848-1860; undated (Box 69)
    - Smith, Elizabeth (Livingston), 1808-1818; undated; incoming only (Box 69)
    - Smith, Garret P. to Peter Smith, 1826 (Box 69)
    - Smith, Gerrit
      - to Ann (Fitzhugh) Smith, 1824-1868; 8 folders (Box 69)
      - to Ann (Fitzhugh) Smith, 1869-1874 (Box 70)
    - Smith, Gerrit (of New York and Brooklyn), 1835-1865 (Box 70)
    - Smith, Gerrit Henry, 1852-1873; undated; 2 folders (Box 70)
    - Smith, Greene and Bessie, circa 1850-1874; to GS and others; 4 folders (Box 70)
    - Smith, Peter
      - to GS, 1814-1825; 5 folders (Box 70)
      - to GS, 1826-1835; 17 folders (Box 71)
      - to GS, 1836-1837; 2 folders (Box 72)
    - Smith, Peter Skenandoah
      - to GS and others, related letters, 1813-1832; 7 folders (Box 72)
      - to GS and others, related letters, 1833-1856; 12 folders (Box 73)
      - to GS and others, related letters, 1857-1858; 2 folders (Box 74)
    - Smith, Sarah (Pogson), 1823-1871; undated; 8 folders (Box 74)
    - Smith, Wealtha Ann (Backus), 1818 (Box 74)
    - Smith, Wyntje, 1795-1834 (Box 74)
    - Smith family, 1813-1818 (Box 74)
    - Talman family, 1840-1874 (Box 74)
    - Taylor, E.L. (cousin?), 1863-1873 (Box 74)
    - Walter, Ellen (Cochrane) and William, 1837-1874; 5 folders (Box 74)
- Business and land files
  - Financial documents
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 75)
    - Account books
      - General, 1822-1825; 1869-1882 (Box 75)
      - Caleb Calkins, daybook (vol.3A), 1840-1859 (Volume 3A)
      - Caleb Calkins, daybook (vol.3B), 1840-1859 (Volume 3B)
      - Caleb Calkins, daybook (vol.3C), 1840-1859 (Box 75)
      - Charity, 1854 (Box 75)
      - Debts
        - Lists of debts owed by Gerrit Smith, including all debts from his late father (vol.4), 1837-1844 (Box 75)
        - Debts due from Gerrit Smith to the People of the State of New York (vol.5), 1837-1851 (Box 75)
        - Lists of debts due in Land Book D (vol.6), 1826-1833 (Box 75)
        - Lists of debts (vol.6A), 1833-1834 (Box 75)
        - Debts due in Land Book E (vol.7); List of debtors and debts (vol.7A and 7B), 1838-1842; 3 volumes in 1 folder (Box 75)
        - Debts due in Land Book F (vol.8), 1845-1847 (Box 76)
        - Debts due in Land Book G-1 (vol.9), 1848-1851 (Box 76)
        - Debts due in Land Book G-M (vol.10), 1852-1857 (Box 76)
        - Debts due in Land Book G-N (vol.11), 1857-1903 (Box 76)
      - Household expenses
        - Daybook, Gerrit Smith debtor to Asa Raymond and John G. Curtis (vol.12), 1827-1837 (Box 76)
        - Daybook (vol.12A), 1829-1838 (Box 76)
        - Daybook, Gerrit Smith debtor to Asa Raymond and John G. Curtis (vol.13), 1837-1842 (Box 76)
        - Daybook, including wages paid (vol.14), 1849-1850 (Box 77)
        - Daybook (vol.15), 1850-1853 (Box 77)
        - Daybook, including wages paid (vol.16), 1853-1856 (Box 77)
        - Daybook, including wages paid (vol.17), 1853-1857 (Box 77)
        - Daybook, [C.D. Miller?] (vol.18), 1856-1857 (Box 77)
        - Daybook, wages paid (vol.18A), 1839-1842 (Box 77)
        - Daybook, Gerrit Snith Miller (vol.19), 1890 (Box 77)
        - Daybook, Miss Lincoln, Peterboro (vol.20), 1896; This item not filmed by MCA (Box 77)
        - Daybook (vol.21), 1863-1870 (Box 77)
      - Traveling expenses
        - Expenses for Gerrit Smith (vol.22), 1869 (Box 77)
        - Board book with Federal Dana and Andrew P. Lord, Peterboro Temperance House (vol.22A), 1831-1835 (Box 77)
        - Expenses for Gerrit Smith (vol.22B), 1845 (Box 77)
        - Expenses (vol.22C), 1877-1878 (Box 77)
    - Accounts
      - Miscellaneous, 1810-1835; undated (Box 77)
      - Miscellaneous, 1836-1874 (Box 78)
      - Miscellaneous daily accounts for Gerrit Smith, 1822-1872; 4 folders (Box 78)
      - Abstracts for Oswego Canal Co., Oswego Hotel, and Oswego pier Dock Co., undated (Box 78)
      - Family
        - Backus, Frederick W., 1849-1859 (Box 78)
        - Baird, Cornelia W.S., 1865-1866 (Box 78)
        - Barclay, Cornelia (Cochrane), 1842-1866 (Box 78)
        - Biddle, Mary L. (Cochrane), 1843-1870 (Box 78)
        - Cochrane, James and Catherine (Cochrane) Kemeys, 1829-1832 (Box 78)
        - Cochrane, James W., 1862-1881 (Box 79)
        - Cochrane, Peter, 1837-1841 (Box 79)
        - Cochrane family, 1841 (Box 79)
        - Fitzhugh, Henry, 1825-1865; 2 folders (Box 79)
        - Fitzhugh family, 1829-1869 (Box 79)
        - Kemeys, Catherine S. (Cochrane), 1847-1854 (Box 79)
        - Miller, Charles D., 1866-1868 (Box 79)
        - Pitcher, Emily Backus, 1871 (Box 79)
        - Smíth, Ann C. (Fitzhugh), 1867-1874 (Box 79)
        - Smith, Peter (with Gerrit Smith), 1819-1837 (Box 79)
        - Smith, Peter Skenandoah, 1810-1855; undated; 4 folders (Box 79)
        - Smith, Sarah (Pogson), 1826-1870 (Box 79)
        - Walter, Ellen Cochrane and William H., 1837-1872 (Box 79)
      - Individuals
        - Bissell, G.W., 1859-1881 (Box 80)
        - Calkins, Caleb, 1848-1866; 2 folders (Box 80)
        - Dorrance, D.G., 1810-1862; 2 folders (Box 80)
        - Edwards, J.B., 1845-1874; 2 folders (Box 80)
        - Fuller, Henry, 1840-1845; 2 folders (Box 80)
        - Gold, Theodore, 1825-1830 (Box 80)
        - Jenkins, Timothy and Hiram, 1853-1863 (Box 81)
        - Jones, David S., 1831-1843 (Box 81)
        - Montgomery, Thomas C., 1851-1869 (Box 81)
      - Littlefield property, 1859-1863 (Box 81)
      - Oswego Hotel, 1840-1853 (Box 81)
      - Oswego Pier and Dock Co., 1852-1856 (Box 81)
      - Rents, 1822-1879; undated (Box 81)
      - Settlement of estate of Peter Smith, 1837, "Book of Explanations, regarding settlement of estate and Gerrit Smith's assumption of land holdings in 1819 (vol.109), circa 1819-1847 (Volume 109)
      - Town of Smithfield, 1851-1852 (Box 81)
    - Bank account books
      - New York State Bank (vol.23 through vol.27), 1846-1866; 5 volumes (Box 81)
      - Syracuse City Bank (vol.27A and 27B), 1857-1867; 2 volumes (Box 81)
    - Bank notes, 1804-1860 (Box 82)
    - Bills and receipts
      - Undated (Box 82)
      - 1802-1824, 23 folders (Box 82)
      - 1824-1827, 7 folders (Box 83)
      - 1828-1830, 7 folders (Box 84)
      - 1831-1834, 8 folders (Box 85)
      - 1835-1840, 11 folders (Box 86)
      - 1841-1847, 7 folders (Box 87)
      - 1848-1854, 10 folders (Box 88)
      - 1855-1857, 8 folders (Box 89)
      - 1858-1862, 7 folders (Box 90)
      - 1863-1867, 6 folders (Box 91)
      - 1868-1870, 6 folders (Box 92)
      - 1871-1872, 8 folders (Box 93)
      - 1873-1879, 8 folders (Box 94)
    - Cash books, accounts of disbursements and receipts
      - (vol.28, 29, 30, 31), 1827-1837; 4 volumes (Box 94)
      - (vol.32, 33, 34), 1837-1848; 3 volumes (Box 95)
      - (vol.35), 1849-1855 (Volume 35)
      - (vol.36, 37), 1856-1876; 2 volumes (Box 95)
    - Checks, cancelled
      - [General], 1834-1837; 1855-1856,; 1859-1872; 11 folders (Box 96)
      - [General], 1873-1874; 2 folders (Box 97)
    - Check stubs
      - (vol.38), 1840-1849 (Box 97)
      - (vol.39), 1859 (Volume 39)
      - (vol.40 through 44), 1850-1863; 5 volumes (Box 97)
      - (vol.45, 46, 47), 1860-1874; 3 volumes (Box 98)
    - Income tax, 1863-1870 (Box 98)
    - Insurance policies, 1828-1872 (Box 98)
    - Loans outstanding, 1828-1849 (Box 98)
  - Land Documents
    - Auctions of property, 1841-1846 (Box 98)
    - Index to ledger A, Florence lands, undated (Box 98)
    - Description of lots and acreage, 1824-1868
      - Township #9 East, part of the Old Military Tract (vol.47a), undated (Box 98)
      - Hardenburgh Patent, Great Lot. 2 (vol.47b), undated (Box 98)
      - Township #23, McCombs Purchase (vol.47c), undated (Box 98)
      - Township ll7, Old Military Tract (vol.47d), undated (Box 98)
      - Lands in Ontario and Cayuqa Counties (vol.47e), undated (Box 98)
      - Lands in Otsego and Schoharie Counties (vol.47f), undated (Box 98)
      - Northwest part of the Oneida indian Reservation (vol.47g), undated (Box 98)
      - Lands in Oneida and Lewis Counties (vol.47h), undated (Box 98)
      - Lands in Herkimer County (vol.47i), undated (Box 98)
      - Lands in northern New York State (vol.47j), undated (Box 98)
      - Lands in Onondaga, Seneca, Yates and Allegany Counties (vol.47k), undated (Box 98)
      - Lands in Broome, Cortland and Chenango Counties (vol.47L), 1830s (Box 98)
      - Townships #9, 10 & 11 of the Old Military Tract (vols.47m and 47m1), undated (Box 99)
      - Land in Phelps and Gorham's Purchase (vol.47n), undated (Box 99)
      - Lands in Sullivan, Ulster, Orange and Greene Counties (vol.47o), undated (Box 99)
      - Land in Essex County (vol.47p), undated (Box 99)
      - Land in Warren County (vol.47q), undated (Box 99)
      - Land in Cattaraugus County (vol.47r), 1867-1868 (Box 99)
      - "Peter Smith, Remarks, Ch[arlotte] River Patent and Byrne's patent,1818 Ec" (vol.48), 1831; miscellaneous lands (Box 99)
      - Lands in Wayne, Cayuga and Oswego Counties (vol.49), with another notebook, unidentified (vol.49a), undated (Box 99)
      - Loose papers, undated; 2 folders (Box 99)
      - Report of the Commissioners of the Land Office...Requiring a detailed Statement of all the unsold lands..." (Albany: Croswell & Van Benthuysen), 1829; printed item (Box 99)
      - Lands in many New York State counties purchased at tax sales and given to Federal Dana to sell (vol.50), 1835-[ ] (Box 100)
      - "Dana Book No. 1" and "Dana Book No. 2", lands in many New York State counties purchased at tax sales in 1814 & 1815 and given to Federal Dana to sell (vols.50a and 50b), 1824; also includes some loose papers (Box 100)
    - Land book, list of names and addresses by county and state of people in debt to Gerrit Smith for land (vol.51), undated (Box 100)
    - Lists of lands to be sold by New York State for arrears of taxes
      - [Lands to be sold for arrears of taxes] (vol.51a), 1813; printed item (Box 100)
      - Lists of Lands to be sold in November 1815, for Arrears of Taxes. (Albany: J. Buel) (vol.51b), printed item (Box 100)
      - List of Patents of Lands, etc. to be Sold in November, 1815 for Arrears of Quit Rent (Albany: J. Buel) (vol.51c), printed item (Box 100)
      - List of Lands to be Sold in October, 1819, for Arrears of Taxes. (Albany: I.W. Clark, 1819) (vol.51d), printed item (Box 100)
      - Lands to be sold for arrears of taxes (vol.52), 1821; printed item (Box 100)
      - List of Patents of Lands, etc. to be Sold in January, 1822 for Arrears of Quit Rent (Albany: E & E Horsford) (vol.52a), printed item (Box 100)
      - List of Lands to be Sold in January, 1826, for Arrears of Taxes. (Albany: Croswell & Van Benthuysen) (vol.53), 1825; printed item; 2 copies (Box 100)
      - List of Lands to be Sold in April, 1830, for Arrears of Taxes. (Albany: Croswell & Van Benthuysen) (vol.54), 1829; printed item (Box 101)
      - List of Lands to be Sold in March, 1834, for Arrears of Taxes for the years 1827, 1828, 1829 and 1830. (Albany: Croswell, Van Benthuysen and Burt) (vol.55), printed item (Box 101)
      - Lands to be sold for arrears of taxes (vol.55a), 1836?; printed item (Box 101)
      - List of Lands to be Sold in June, 1843, for Arrears of Taxes for the years 1836, 1837, 1838 and 1839. (Albany: Thurlow Weed) (vol.55b), printed item (Box 101)
      - List of Lands to be Sold for Arrears of Taxes, for the years 1840, 1841, 1842, 1843 & 1844. (Albany: Weed, Parsons & Co.) (vol.55b1), 1848; printed item (Box 101)
      - List of Lands to be Sold for Arrears of Taxes, for the years 1845, 1846, 1847, 1848. (Albany: Weed, Parsons & Co.) (vol.55b2), 1853; printed item (Box 102)
      - List of Lands to be Sold for Arrears of Taxes, for the years 1852, 1853, 1854 & 1855... (Albany: Weed, Parsons & Co.) (vol.55c), 1859; printed item (Box 102)
      - List of Lands to be Sold for Arrears of Taxes, for the years 1856, 1857, 1858, 1859 & 1860... (Albany: Weed, Parsons & Co.) printed item (vol.55c1), 1866 (Box 102)
      - List of Lands to be Sold for Arrears of Taxes, for the years 1861, 1862, 1863, 1864 & 1865... (Albany: The Argus Company) (vol.55d), 1871; printed item (Box 102)
      - List of Lands to be Sold for Arrears of Taxes, for the years 1871, 1872, 1873, 1874, 1875 & 1876... (Albany: Weed, Parsons & Co.) (vol.55d1), 1881; printed item (Box 102)
      - Statement of Lands Sold for Taxes. By Virtue of Several Acts of the Legislature of the State of New York, from 14th Sept. 1808 to 1st March 1821 (Albany: Weed, Parsons & Co.) (vol.5e1), 1881; printed item (Box 102)
      - [Statement of lands sold for taxes by the State of New York] (vol.55e), 1825-1830; printed item (Box 103)
      - Statement of all the Lands Sold by the Comptroller...Prior to the Sale of 1848...at the Sales of 1834, 1839 & 1843 (Albany: Weed, Parsons & Co.) (vol.56), printed item (Box 103)
      - Description of lands in Allegany, Broome, Cayuga, Chenango & Cortland Counties that were sold for arrears of taxes (vol.57), 1838-1839 (Volume 57)
    - List of land holdings